Roland Delgado

Full-Stack Web Developer

Over 15 years of customer service experience and over 3 years of team leading experience. Eager to utilize newfound technical skills in Web Development and pursue further knowledge in the field. Graduate of the University of Miami Coding Bootcamp (Full-Stack Web Development) and possesses an AA degree from Miami Dade College.

Education

2022-11 - Full-Stack Web Development Certificate

2023-05 University of Miami - Miami, FL

2006-09 - Associate of Arts

2008-08 Miami Dade College - Miami, FL

Certifications

2023-05 Full-Stack Web Development

Work History

Current

2021-02 - Patient Access Specialist

University Of Miami, Miami, FL

- Collected and validated patient demographics and insurance information.
- Performed patient pre-admission, admission, transfer, and discharge activities.
- Obtained signatures from financial responsibility and treatment procedures from patients or guardians.
- Trained new staff on hospital processes and procedures.
- Stayed calm under pressure to and successfully dealt with difficult situations.

2020-11 - Senior Patient Access Representative

2021-02 University of Miami, Miami, FL

Contact

Address

Miami, Florida 33126

Phone

(305)484-3310

E-mail

webdevrodel@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/roland-delgado-7942372

WWW

https://ohnoitsro.github.io/react-portfolio/

Skills

Javascript

Very Good

HTML

Excellent

CSS

Excellent

JQuery

Good

React.js

Very Good

- Collected and entered patient demographic and insurance data into computer database to establish patient's medical record.
- Received patient deductibles and co-pay amounts and discussed options to satisfy remainder of patient financial obligations.
- Utilized knowledge of electronic medical record systems and medical terminology to perform diverse data entry tasks.
- Providing excellent customer service by promptly answering patient inquiries.

2018-08 - Patient Access Representative

2020-11

2018-07

University Of Miami, Miami, FL

- Performed patient scheduling and registration functions to serve as initial contact point for medical office visits.
- Secured patient information and confidential medical records in compliance with HIPAA privacy rule standards to protect patient's privacy.
- Applied administrative knowledge and courtesy to explain procedures and services to patients.
- Processed payments using cash and credit cards, maintaining accurate records of transactions.
- Obtained patient's insurance information and determined eligibility for benefits for specific services rendered.

2008-10 - Lead Coordinator

Century Marketplace, Miami, FL

- Gathered and organized materials to support operations.
- Inventoried and ordered office supplies to maintain availability of products.
- Entered data, generated reports, and produced tracking documents.
- Coached employees through day-to-day work and complex problems.
- Improved new advertising that brought in extra revenue (around \$2000) monthly.

Express

Very Good

Node.js

Very Good

MongoDB/mySQL



Handlebars



Bootstrap/Materialize/MUI



Insomnia/GraphQL



GitHub



Heroku

Very Good

Languages

Bilingual in English and Spanish